veligeti.murali@gmail.com +91 9686544544 Bangalore, India

Expert-level Software Architect who has more than 13 years of experience developing proprietary enterprise software products and has optimum excitement in using various technologies to design, develop, and attentively deploy real enterprise class software, including building a knowledge of customer's environments and their use of products. Self motivated with the ability to be proactive with project execution.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior System Architect

Huawei Technologies India Pvt Ltd

02/2015 - Present Achivements / Task

- Designed and Developed Microservices and interaction between them.
- Designed and Created private cloud set using Docker and Kubernetes. Worked on SDC ONAP module
- Developed shared central authentication system in Java/AngularJS for intranet applications.
- Collaborated with product management to design, build and test systems.
- Collaborated with developers and performance engineers to enhance supportability and identify performance
- Contributed Python codebase used in the automated deployment of software on multiple virtual machines.
- Worked closely with clients to establish problem specifications and system designs.
- Created, delivered and maintained scalable system architecture to support a high-availability internet site with various internal applications.
- Performed regression and system-level testing to verify software quality and function before it was released.

Lead Engineer

Nalashaa Solutions LLC

03/2014 - 02/2015 Achivements / Task

- Involved in identifying performance issues and enhance the code to resolve bottlenecks in the customer environment.
- Evaluated multiple software solutions during early software architecture plotting and system migration planning stage.
- Developed Integration Platform for different systems such as SAP and CRM system.
- Optimized the existing application for the customer by implementing web sockets based solution.
- Implemented designs, including experimentation and multiple iterations.
- Diagnosed and troubleshooting UNIX and Windows processing problems and applied solutions to increase company
- Provided methodologies for object-oriented software development and efficient database design
- Designed and implemented new server standards for core business services.
- Recommended architectural improvements, design solutions and integration solutions
- Used to do lot of research in identifying new technologies and tools for enhancing product value and increasing team

Senior Consultant

British Telecom

- 05/2013 03/2014 Achivements / Task
- Involved in evaluation of multiple solutions and multiple open source products to identify best suitable product for
- Involved in developing Use Case document and written High Level Design and Low Level Design.
- Built, tested and deployed scalable, highly available and modular software products.
- Involved in performance testing to verify software quality and function before it was released.
- Worked closely with other team members to plan, design and develop robust solutions in a timely manner.
- Assessed costs and risks associated with developing new features and products.
- Interacts with Software Vendors Oracle and IBM to solve the problems raised in the product.
- Used tools such as JProfiler and MAT tools to identify performance bottlenecks in the application and revamped the application using the latest technologies such as HTML5 and Emberjs.
- Implemented continuous integration tools in deployment process.

Senior Software Engineer

Oracle India Pvt Ltd

02/2009 - 05/2013 Achivements / Task

- Interact with Portal product/Server product support team, investigating and diagnosing problems, instrumenting code to identify bugs and fixing them in the code level, and providing optimal solutions to the customer.
- Worked on reproducing Production issues on Portal/Server installers and debugging the code to find the fix for the problems.
- Worked on bug fixes in the Portal product related to WSRP 2.0, UCM VCR Adapter, Content Management, DVT (Dynamic Visitor Tools), Personalization, Interaction Management, REST API, DISC API.
- Worked on issues in Server product related to WebApp, JDBC, JMS, Memory Leaks and Performance Issues.
- Worked on developing software which helps to collect the logs files from customer environment when memory issues comes in production server and also helps in providing possible solutions when problem occurs.
- Involved in writing complex logic for server performance to improve. Had rewritten the entire module for JMS performance.

- Involving in managing and maintain code and configurations for all the future and previous version of the product.

- Worked as consultant and involved in onsite engagements for Architecture Design review, Performance Tuning and
- Involved in development Oracle Cloud software.
- Involved in designing, development and testing of features via applications and services.

Software Engineer

IT People Corporation India Pvt Ltd

- 08/2008 02/2009 Achivements / Task
- Evaluated existing applications to reprogram, update and add new features. - Designed and developed prototypes according to specifications.
- Identified and resolved performance and scaling issues in the existing applications.
- Developed applications with high quality source code within deadlines.

Associate - IT Services

Mindtree Pvt Ltd

04/2008 - 08/2008 - Achivements / Task

- Collecting information on project and developed some of the use cases.
- Worked on building REST API and code modularization.
- Worked on implementing CI environment which does builds automatically.
- Involved in doing Proof of Concept using Spring/Hibernate and successfully completed.
- Involved in writing High Level Design by considering Use Case document.
- Worked on developing JUNITs and done 100% code coverage.

Software Technical Consultant

CRMIT Solutions Pvt Ltd

05/2006 - 04/2008

- Achivements / Task Involved in developing prototypes to confirm feasibility of the solution.
- Researched, designed and implemented scalable applications for information identification, extraction, analysis, retrieval and indexing.
- Wrote maintainable and extensible code in a team environment.
- Worked effectively with design teams to ensure software solutions elevated client side experience.
- Modified existing software to correct errors, upgrade interfaces and improve performance.
- Prepared detailed reports concerning project specifications and activities.
- Developed code fixes and enhancements for inclusion in future code releases and patches.
- Collaborated with developers and performance engineers to enhance supportability and identify performance
- Fast in debugging customer problems and provide optimal solutions.

SKILLS

Spring Cloud

Apach Spark

Pandas

Java (J2EE, EJB, JSP, JNI, Servlets, Log4j)

Web Services (SOAP, WSDL, REST API)

AWS Docker Node.js

Cloud Foundry Kubernetes

Apache Kafka

Cloud Foundry

Hibernate Weblogic Server

Rabbit MQ

Webcenter Portal Weblogic Portal

Netflix OSS components(Eureka, Zuul, Hystrix)

Huawei Cloud Microservices

EDUCATION

Master Of Engineering ME

Arunai Engineering College [Anna University] 08/2003 - 06/2005

Bachelor Of Technlogy BTech

Arunai Engineering College [University Of Madras] 08/1999 - 04/2003

AWARDS AND RECOGNITION

- Involved in developing prototypes to confirm feasibility of the solution.
- Received Director award for performing excellence in Design and development of project for Singtel and AIS.
- Top Coder across Huawei India 2017 (For high code contribution with good quality).
- Excellence in Project Delivery 2016 (This award is meant for delivering project with good quality).
- Excellence in Project Delivery 2015 (This award is meant for delivering project with good quality).
- Outstanding Contributor Award for FY10 Q2 (For contributing in the area of Weblogic Portal Knowledge Management. This award has an Executive VP level visibility at Oracle.)
- Spot Award for FY10, Q3 (These awards are used to recognize individuals that have demonstrated commitment to their job and to helping others, whether a customer or teammate. Considerations include commitment & dedication to a goal or project and consistent high performance.)
 - **OSCAR** Award Nominee for Rookie FY10.
- Star Award for FY11, Q4 (These awards are used to recognize individuals that have demonstrated commitment to their job and to helping others, whether a customer or teammate. Considerations include commitment & dedication to a goal or project and consistent
- high performance.) Star Award for FY13. Q1 (These awards are used to recognize individuals that have demonstrated commitment to their job and to helping others, whether a customer or teammate. Considerations include commitment & dedication to a goal or project and consistent high performance.